Ivan Palmegiani, MSc

Berlin - Germany

ivan.palmegiani@gmail.com | LinkedIn Account | GitHub Account



Profile

Scientist with strong analytical mindset. Advanced technical skills developed over 5+ years working experience, and intensive training. Excellent communication skills. Team worker, also able to take charge of tasks individually. Highly motivated and positive towards challenges. Curious and eager to learn. Constructive critical thinker.

Expertise

R coding | Python programming | Relational databases (SQL) | Geographic Information Systems (GIS) | Exploratory data analyses (EDA) | Hypothesis testing | Inferential and predictive modelling | Time series analyses and forecast | Data visualization | Data reporting | Research

References

Alexandre Courtiol, PhD Senior Researcher at IZW - Leibniz Institute for Zoo and Wildlife Research **Laura Iacolina, PhD** Assistant Professor at University of Primorska

Professional Experience

Freelance Data Scientist | Quantitative Analyst, June 2018 - Present

IZW - Leibniz Institute for Zoo and Wildlife Research

PhD Candidate, May 2014 - Jun. 2018 | Research Assistant, Apr. 2013 - Sept. 2013

Collect and analyze large time series of geo-referenced data with Kernel Density Estimation (KDE), Movement-based KDE (MKDE), Brownian Bridges Movement Models (BBMM), Local Convex Hulls (LoCoH), K-nearest neighbors algorithms (k-NN), Random-walks. Model environmental dynamics with linear and non-linear regression models. Query relational geo-data sets with SQL. Data visualization and report to stake-holders and team members. Write scientific papers. Organize scientific symposia.

CIBIO - Research Center in Biodiversity and Genetic Resources

Research Assistant, Dec. 2012 - Feb. 2013 | Research Technician, Feb. 2012 - Nov. 2012 Exploratory data analyses (EDA). Collect and analyze GPS telemetry and environmental data. Model presence/absence data with generalized linear models (GLM). Design and maintain relational geo-databases (SQL). Write scientific papers. Report data to stake-holders and scientific audiences.

Page 1/2 Resume - Ivan Palmegiani

Department of Zoology and Evolutionary Genetics, University of Sassari

Research Technician, Nov. 2010 - Nov. 2011

Collect geo-referenced environmental data. Collect bio-acoustic data, sonograms analyses. Collection and analyses of presence/absence data through camera-trapping surveys. **Teaching experience**: lecturer on wildlife monitoring and surveys methods.

Education

Master of Science (MSc), Jul. 2010 *Environmental science and natural resources management*, University of Sassari. Grade: 110/110 *cum Laude*

Environmental modelling, statistical inference, advanced statistical theory, zoocenosis and wildlife conservation, wildlife management, genetics, plant conservation, environmental economics, systems ecology, landscape ecology, regional geology, sedimentology.

Languages

English (IELTS certification level C1) • German (TELC certification level B1) • Italian (mother tongue) • Spanish (fluent) • Portuguese (fluent).

Hobbies and interests

Outdoor sports and activities such as climbing, bouldering, hiking, biking, canoeing, camping • Indoor gardening • Urban farming • DIY and Handicraft • Music and Arts.

Page 2/2 Resume - Ivan Palmegiani